[Music]
all right so moving on to the next
chapter so we obviously are saving time
in our online highly highly available uh
service but how are we saving time for
consultants and this is an interesting
story so uh I wanted to uh invite on
stage a colleague of mine but today she
happens to be my
consultant and I'm a very curious and
very anxious uh customer who has an
experience to go through so this is my
morning and this is my trusty consultant
so please help me welcome on stage
[Music]
Ida how are you doing today hi Dimitri
you sound very very concerned on the
phone so what's going on today yeah yes
so um let let me show you something so
you know what
um let me just um you
know give it a second you're going to
you're going to not love it you know I
did not love it but by the way the last
three months were amazing so the last
three months the service was super
performant highly available resilient
loved it today look at this so I'm on my
list of orders mhm and uh I click on
this order are you ready to witness this
it throws this error which says volume
error I mean I couldn't make up anything
of this like I don't even know what to
what to do next like what am I doing
here you know what I I not that I think
it makes any difference I'm just going
to go ahead and say that no this
information was not helpful at all yeah
sure but you know what first of all it
makes a difference all of this is going
to capture in Telemetry and I don't know
I can't spot my colleague Kenny here but
I'm sure he already got a notification
and jump hi can out of his mobile phone
so this is going to be captured but I
agree with you volum errror what does
that supposed to mean so let me
investigate Fair could you please close
this errow my eyes beding absolutely
absolutely literally absolutely thank
you thank you so to investigate further
I'm going to my favorite section help
and
support and in
here maybe not in front of 3,000 people
but maybe I'm going to try actually this
beautiful new in the new release of
business Central you can actually
directly attach the debugger to this
session from the client and I'm going
just to do
that hey that's
amazing that is amazing right so let's
see what is going to happen
great and look at here the debugger is
already on you know so you didn't need
to set up things and configuration files
especially because now I just run the
scope of this current project so the
debugger is on and now all I need to do
is to go and reproduce this error and
see what happens great let me get back
it was your look to the side I cannot
bear the experience of seeing this errow
once again I don't think look what
happened
I guess something happening on the other
side It Go and directly stop on the
volume error isn't this
awesome and you know
here look at this code it's quite simple
to read what is happening here is just
it seems like some dimension on this
item is set to zero or less than zero
and therefore this error but honestly
how you could have figured this out
right I needed to attach the debugger
life in front of 3,000 people that we
figure this out I'm sure something can
be done about this and absolutely with
this release of business Central I am
able to go and make this error
actionable and you know if you take a
look on this extension I think the
developer already start to use this
actionable errors but missed on this
error so so I'm going to do that but I'm
always a little bit nervous coding on a
stage so I'm going to summon my AI paid
programmer GitHub co-pilot and hopefully
it doesn't disappoint me so let's try so
what I'm going to do here let's
see I'm going to do you want to stop the
debugger ah very good let me stop the
debugger we don't need you anymore now
co-piloting action
great so I'm going
to and let's see what happens wow this
is exactly what I wanted it a magic
let's try
again it's worth seeing for the second
time for sure it's wonderful and did you
see the magic that happened by the way
couldn't you just copy paste the disc
code from a few lines
above the me
where in yesterday keynote that was like
before co-pilot era copy pasting now I
have co-pilot and of course I can go and
copy paste think about the contents what
is it but this is exactly directly in
the context of what I'm trying to do
which is the item and it's already done
for me I don't think I could have come
up with a better error message with
referencing the item number so it's all
already there for me and if you remember
Mike Morton said yesterday say when you
use this don't get very excited check
the code once or twice I'm going to do
that here and I can see here a small
error so it should be item card right so
I'm going to fix that because I wanted
to refer to the item card and that's it
I think I have it ready I'm going to
compile and run this yeah let's put my
sand to my sandbox to see what's going
on there see what's going to
happen great let's
see actionable error in
action all right running and running can
can I can I try yeah you sure go all
right so so I click on this guy
again hey the item the item number has
no Dimensions like this is this is much
more actionable like now at least now I
know which item is causing this issue oh
you miss something else look at here
open item page so you can direct this is
White Glove service I mean yeah you can
directly go to this and you know no code
required here so if you actually had
this already you know you didn't need to
even call me and S like that on the
phone I'm blocked I can't open my I only
wish I could like this error message
three
times such an amazing experience yeah by
the way look it gets me straight to the
cards and you know get some clue from
the code one of the dimensions probably
zero and I exactly see that this classic
Amsterdam lamp has no Heights let's give
it a height and then hopefully after
that we are going to be good to go I
think your error is fixed now fantastic
hey look we are on this cards and I have
another question for you so good that
you're here with me like look I was
playing with this item tring field okay
and I need to set up item tring for my
lamp and you know there there's there's
many CES codes available here and every
time I select a different code it comes
up with some message you know something
is this something is that is there a way
to figure out what kind of checks this
thing is doing so I understand what is
what is possible with item tracking code
I think you like to put me on a spot
here today like look at this yeah is
isn't that a daily life of consultant
everybody knows that I have a very good
understanding of business Central
application but when it comes to item
tracking I'm a bit
Rusty so I have let me think two maybe
three option here option number one is
ask of item tracking group my colleague
Andre to come on a stage great idea but
should I put him on a spot I don't want
to option number two go and read bunch
of
documentation and option number three
which I normally love is going to all
imate documentation which is code behind
this field and I'm going to try that I
love the sound of that yeah let's see so
code is the ultimate documentation for
this I'm going to uh actually uh invoke
or summon the page inspector we are
summoning many many nice great
Technologies today let's see very good
and it already tells me what page I on
what item and I can just go and search I
don't want to even go and look at the
fields you can filter and everything but
I know it's tracking so let me go find
that here you go item tracking code and
look at here I love
this with a simple direct action from
the client I can go and a
straight and I have already downloaded
the symbol jump to the code isn't this
awesome you know wow
this is incredible I didn't need to scan
through thousands and thousands of
application objects find the page I'm
exactly on the relevant page placed on
the field so now I'm going to use I'm
not the only one excited about this I
mean I hear a very good vibe from the
crowd all right let's let's take a look
let's take a look so what did you want
you wanted to see what does this feel
checks right yeah exactly exactly what
kind of checks be do let me do my code
code reading abilities you
know I'm consultant I can read a bit of
code let me look look look wow look at
here there is a wall of code here yeah I
can go and try to understand this or
summon my second friend my AI advisor
giop copilot chat and you know what I'm
going to do that because maybe it can
explain to
me let me ask
asking what does Dimitri wants to know
no what does this
code
check for H interesting I would like to
be polite please list it Mak sense
Dimitri wants it no we don't have time
for that let's see you know you see AI
is the only thinking as well it's not
only me and
you hey I recognize this let me see hey
wait wait wait wait wait wait look I can
read the code now guys everyone hey look
at this dri it's English it's not the
code ah no wonder I was able to
recognize this H close enough code
English but look okay so so I I can
actually make some sense out of it so it
checks for different parameters it
checks if old item tricking code exists
it checks if a specific tracking has
changed it checks if the warehouse
tracking has changed the costing methods
there's even some expiration calculation
happening whether it's empty or not wow
this is quite interesting actually I got
I like even without looking at the code
I got some insights into it so you know
what uh I I I think I will keep it
simple so I'll just go ahead and assign
this uh free entry tracking code so you
don't need I don't need all of these
calculations and validation this is fine
very good so just to make sure I do my
job right so you wanted to fix your
sales order we figure out the item card
you also ask for tracking now you know
more than maybe Andre about it I don't
know I'm sure after reading all of these
codes exactly so let me go and U just
get back and make sure that the sales
order can open now because we fixed
everything right so let's open the sales
order very nice so the sales order is
open and my case is closed so I can
go yeah you wish you could
go is this the one is this the one you
wish you would go but I wanted to show
you something no you can show me
something so look uh now when we are on
the sales order
page what are you opening here um so
here here's a report here's a report
that I have and you know what every time
when I uh work with this report so like
just what time I work with this report
every time actually when I work with the
order I keep flipping back and forth you
know order report order reports I want
to look up data on my inventory I want
to see what what sells best and what
sells worst and I want to use the power
of powerbi to to give me these insights
and I have this this visual which which
was built here like look the Fantastic
it's it's powered by AI by the way but I
want it on my page can I please have it
right there so I don't have to flip
around I wonder why today you have
you're asking all this right questions
from Me Maybe not before but actually
with this release of Business Center
you can go to a report select the visual
that you love and
directly put it in the context of your
page and for that it's very simple do
you want to do it now it's actually of
course I'm actually starting to like
this 2023 whatever release it is a lot
you know and all you need to do is to go
to the BCT Tech I'm kind of all I need
to go I'm the consultant right I go to
the bcch
and there very nice samples available I
look at the sample samples and
guidelines and read the guidelines and
figure out what to do I need to add a
fact box and a trigger to initiate it
just like that so but to initiate that
trigger what should I do I need two
things the report ID of course and the
visual ID so for that I can simply go
here and try to take the link find the
link and at the moment I copy this URL
in the guidelines you will also see it I
find the report ID is there and also I
find the uh visual ID and copy that in
my clip code and go directly add it to
my code and I'm going to do that for you
today so I have already copied those
from BC sample I'm going to add it here
this is your layout so let me go and add
that fact box
here just copy paste it's exact copy
paste from that I prepar the snippet
good so I have this fact box which host
the visualization right and then I need
to go a little bit down here and just
add the trigger as well that's it it's
the one lineer one single line I just
add the trigger very good I copy paste
that again all right and just replace
those two IDs in this it's in here and
uh just you can see so there's one ID
here and another ID there and then I
just run this publish it to
my yeah we're making so much so much
progress progress with you Ida today I
mean this is incredible see what happens
you're such a highly valuable
consultant I'm working with a highly
time I'm saving
let's see so do you want to have the
honor of trying this all right let's
give me a try so I'll I'll just grab
this
order okay and so let's take a look at
fact boxes hey there something is
loading powerbi
reports okay loading data from there and
there it is hey this is
incredible like
look now I can make data driven decision
right here from the p page where the
data is like this is it complement the
data in BC in such a nice way and it was
quite it looked quite easy to Ed it here
so thank you I see my Berlin guest chair
is selling the most I can see you're
very excited but uh I'm super excited
are you done are you sure you're done uh
you know what no no actually I'm I'm not
done I'm not done I will keep you a
little bit more here so here's here's
the thing
um I I was told by my co colleagues that
uh I uh I I they say that I can figure
out how to add a field to a page and you
know what I have this field on the sales
order which they call it the my my evil
colleagues told me that it exists okay
right but it exists on the table and I
tried with all the personalization
things and it just cannot edit and what
field that is but you know what like I
was just trying to see how many times
this document was posted so could you
please use this magic of Visual Studio
code and visual studio copilot to add
these fields to this page I mean it
should be simple it you know you don't
need me for that and you don't need any
of AI magic and all that I have a better
magic here the magic of the beautiful
interface of business Central you as the
customer can go ahead yourself
absolutely you can go and at the field I
can guide you through for the first time
I continue being developer everyone all
right yeah yeah sure such a developer
see so what about you go and find your
profile
okay so let's go to profiles very good
and what is your Prof I use business
manager evaluation then just go ahead in
there and just have this in mind that I
have as your admin give you permission
yep to invoke this action that's
important because you are you know you
are Dimitri you are the power customer
power user so not to everybody then
people go and add the you know Fields
left and right but but I have given you
that permission and that's why you see
that right there customized page that's
fair intive at the moment you click on
that look what happens we should wait
now you have the entire business Central
customization mode in the customization
mode all right and you can go ahead and
add a field to any page you want so what
was the page you wanted yeah so uh I was
actually on the sales uh
orders and let me find that order there
it is okay okay so good this one and no
no no no look that's here that's very
very nice plus sign oh very intuitive
add a field very good and then you know
you can filter the fields so if you know
where it is or you want to see a
selection but do you know what is the
name of the field you oh absolutely
absolutely it's something about printed
just and I'm I'm pretty sure it's on the
page there it is number printed number
printed okay so let me click on this
it's added to the page and say add just
a little add Okay add so now it's here I
have number printed here and you know if
you click again you have other options
like if you want to remove it hide it
show it collapse and all this is a great
experience but now are you done yes yes
are you sure you're done done there's a
button red Dum button not red button red
D button done so very good now you can
close this I cannot wait to see this I
just added the field completely on my
own go and open your sales order again
all right yes and see if it was in
action Let's see we are running all of
this live number printed number printed
right here on the order thank you thank
you so much my dear
consultant all right all right all right
all right this is incredible I mean we
just spent what like um 10 minutes and
got so much things done okay you know
you've written a whole bunch of code
there so um
uh could you please put all of these
code on this flash drive and I want to
put it in my production environment
right away I want all of my users to get
using these features honestly my 13
years old daughter find one of these and
I was asking me Mom what is this and I
try to explain you know what do you mean
you put code on it yeah Dimitri we I
give you a lot of a speech about you
know this is 21st century so we don't
just
you know pass around the code on the
flash drive to each other M I can't also
just shove the code uh from sandbox into
production because all these
capabilities that we see it was on your
sandbox environment so if you want all
of this I have a much better a story for
you so what I can do here I can go and
submit all these changes that I have to
the same safe and secure Cloud
repository in GitHub it is empowered by
algo and then what is great about Alo it
will do all the processes all the
automation that I need to do to ensure
the high quality of the code is it
compatible the code we are adding with
the next version of business Central Mak
sense um runs the performance test if
you had any regression and after all
these checks on after my also colleagues
review that so I am not missing anything
then all I need to go through this
empowered you know go action go and
publish this to the environment so
tomorrow morning when you wake up with
your cup of coffee sitting with your
colleagues you can just have sip your
coffee and enjoy all these nice changes
in your production environment it cannot
get any better than that thank you so
much my dear consult
yes thank you thank you and thank you
Ida thank
you